<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>automation on protiumx blog</title><link>https://protiumx.dev/blog/tags/automation/</link><description>Recent content in automation on protiumx blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://protiumx.dev/blog/tags/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automate an articles section in your github.io page</title><link>https://protiumx.dev/blog/posts/automate-an-articles-section-in-your-github.io-page/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protiumx.dev/blog/posts/automate-an-articles-section-in-your-github.io-page/</guid><description>Today I wanted to update my github page to show a list of my last Medium articles. I ended up automating it.
First approach My first attempt was fetching the RSS feed using the URL medium.com/feed/@username and parse the xml document. But I was hit with a charming CORS error. Now what?
I remembered that I&amp;rsquo;m using a github action to update a similar section on my github profile. So, what if I tell this action that the README file is called index.</description></item><item><title>blogpub@v0.4.1: host media on github for your blog posts</title><link/><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid/><description>Hey everyone, this is just a small update on the blogpub action.
Relative paths In release v0.4.1 I added support for relative paths which means you can now use github to host the media you use in your blog posts. How does it work? Just use relative paths (to the markdown file) and you are ready to go. E.g. The action replaces all relative paths with the raw content github urls.</description></item><item><title>Publish your blog articles everywhere with this github action</title><link>https://protiumx.dev/blog/posts/publish-your-blog-articles-everywhere-with-this-github-action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protiumx.dev/blog/posts/publish-your-blog-articles-everywhere-with-this-github-action/</guid><description>Long ago I made this comment in this article:
This is a really good idea with great potential. Imagine a standarized API for different blogs. You can automatize publishing and editing, multiple collaborators. and use a git provider as unique source of content. And you can also make your git repo as some sort of blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll use it for my next posts for sure. Thanks!
It was an idea that I had left on the back of my head and I didn&amp;rsquo;t come back to it because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t writing articles actively.</description></item></channel></rss>